artbeads.com 2018-07-04

# Privacy & Security

**Privacy Policy  
**Protecting your private information is our priority. This Statement of Privacy applies to www.artbeads.com and PROTOCOL II, Inc., dba Artbeads.com and governs data collection and usage. For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, unless otherwise noted, all references to PROTOCOL II, Inc., dba Artbeads.com include www.artbeads.com and Artbeads. The Artbeads website is an ecommerce site. By using the Artbeads website, you consent to the data practices described in this statement.

**Collection of your Personal Information  
**Artbeads may collect personally identifiable information, such as your name, address, email address, and phone number.  

If you purchase Artbeads's products and services, we collect billing and credit card information. This information is used to complete the purchase transaction.

Artbeads may also collect anonymous demographic information, which is not unique to you, such as your age, gender, interests, and skill level.

We may gather additional personal or non-personal information in the future.

Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information or personally sensitive data through Artbeads's public product reviews, questions & answers, or social media pages, this information may be collected and used by others.

Artbeads encourages you to review the privacy statements of websites you choose to link to from Artbeads so that you can understand how those websites collect, use and share your information. Artbeads is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on websites outside of the Artbeads website.

**Use of your Personal Information  
**Artbeads collects and uses your personal information to operate its website(s) and deliver the services you have requested.

Artbeads may also use your personally identifiable information to inform you of other products or services available from Artbeads and its affiliates. Artbeads may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services that may be offered.

Artbeads does not sell, rent or lease its customer lists to third parties.

Artbeads may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases, your unique personally identifiable information (e-mail, name, address, telephone number) is not transferred to the third party. 

Artbeads may keep track of the websites and pages our users visit within Artbeads, in order to determine what Artbeads services are the most popular. This data is used to deliver customized content and advertising within Artbeads to customers whose behavior indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area.

Artbeads will disclose your personal information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on Artbeads or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Artbeads; and, (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of Artbeads, or the public.

**Automatically Collected Information  
**Information about your computer hardware and software may be automatically collected by Artbeads. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring website addresses. This information is used for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the Artbeads website.

**Use of Cookies  
**The Artbeads website may use "cookies" to help you personalize your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the Web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalize Artbeads pages, or register with Artbeads site or services, a cookie helps Artbeads to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, such as billing addresses, shipping addresses, and so on. When you return to the same Artbeads website, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the Artbeads features that you customized.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the Artbeads services or websites you visit.

**Third Party Service Providers  
**Artbeads may also engage third party advertising companies to advertise products or services to you online. These companies may employ cookies, single pixel gifs or web beacons to measure advertising effectiveness. They may also use this technology to serve specialized or relevant advertising content and/or recommendations to you on our site or on a third party's website. Note that any information that these third parties collect via any tracking method is completely anonymous and does not contain any personally identifiable information. If you would like to learn more about network advertisers, including how to opt-out of individual company's ads, please [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp "Network Advertisers").

Artbeads may also engage third party service providers to provide additional functionality on our website. These third parties may collect and/or store data elements for use in providing their services, including, but not limited to, your social media identifier, IP address, browser type, referring/exit pages, and operating system. These data elements will be used solely for the purposes of providing their services and will not be shared with other companies or used for any other purpose.

**Security of your Personal Information  
**Artbeads secures your personal information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. Artbeads uses SSL Protocol for this purpose.

When personal information (such as a credit card number) is transmitted to other websites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) protocol.

**Children Under Thirteen  
**Artbeads does not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of thirteen. If you are under the age of thirteen, you must ask your parent or guardian for permission to use this website.

**Submission of Content  
**By uploading an image, adding a link to a video or by making a comment (hereby referred to as “content”), you represent and warrant to us that (1) doing so does not violate or infringe on anyone else's rights; and (2) you created the content you are uploading or otherwise have sufficient intellectual property rights to upload the content consistent with these terms. With regard to the content, you grant Artbeads.com a non-exclusive, royalty- free, perpetual, irrevocable worldwide license (with sublicense and assignment rights) to use, store, to display online and in any present or future media, to create derivative works of, to allow downloads of, and/or distribute any such content. You also give other Artbeads.com users the right to share your content via various social medial platforms integrated with Artbeads.com. Note that you retain all rights and ownership of your content.

**Product Usage**  
Products sold on this website are intended for use in craft and jewelry projects only. No other use is suggested or intended.

**Trademarks**  
Artbeads®, Artbeads.com®, all page headers, custom graphics and photographs, and button icons are service marks, trademarks, and/or trade dress of Artbeads.com. Product names and company names or logos cited herein may be the property of their respective owners and are used solely to refer to those parties and/or their products. No other use is intended.

**Copyrights**  
All software, web site design, text, graphics, and the arrangement thereof, is Copyright © 1999-2017 by Artbeads.com. ALL RIGHTS RESERVED. Permission is granted to reproduce portions of this web site for the sole purpose of placing an order with Artbeads.com. Any other use of materials on this web site - including reproduction for purposes other than those noted above, modification, distribution, or republication - without the prior written permission of Artbeads.com is strictly prohibited.

Product images are copyrighted by Artbeads.com and may also be copyrighted by the manufacturers of those products or their designers. You may not copy or use these images in any way, except as part of using this web site. Copyrighted images are used on this web site pursuant to 17USC113(c) and no other use is intended. 

**Errors & Omissions**  
It is quite rare, but it does sometimes happen that there is an error, omission, or ambiguity in a published sale, description, or price. When this happens we reserve the right to correct the error or to clarify the description. If you have ordered the item before the correction we may cancel the order and issue you a refund or may make other reasonable adjustments. You may also return the item for a full refund.

**Disconnecting your Artbeads Account from Third Party Websites  
**You will be able to connect your Artbeads account to third party accounts. BY CONNECTING YOUR ARTBEADS ACCOUNT TO YOUR THIRD PARTY ACCOUNT, YOU ACKNOWLEDGE AND AGREE THAT YOU ARE CONSENTING TO THE CONTINUOUS RELEASE OF INFORMATION ABOUT YOU TO OTHERS (IN ACCORDANCE WITH YOUR PRIVACY SETTINGS ON THOSE THIRD PARTY SITES). IF YOU DO NOT WANT INFORMATION ABOUT YOU, INCLUDING PERSONALLY IDENTIFYING INFORMATION, TO BE SHARED INTHIS MANNER, DO NOT USE THE THIS FEATURE. You may disconnect your account from a third party account at any time. Users may disconnect their social media accounts by contacting us via email, chat, or telephone.

**Opt-Out & Unsubscribe  
**We respect your privacy and give you an opportunity to opt-out of receiving announcements of certain information. Users may opt-out of receiving any or all communications from Artbeads by contacting us here:

  * Web page: www.artbeads.com
  * Email: support@artbeads.com
  * Phone: 253-857-3433

**Changes to this Statement  
**Artbeads will occasionally update this Statement of Privacy to reflect company and customer feedback. Artbeads encourages you to periodically review this Statement to be informed of how Artbeads is protecting your information.

**Contact Information  
**Artbeads welcomes your questions or comments regarding this Statement of Privacy. If you believe that Artbeads has not adhered to this Statement, please contact Artbeads at:

PROTOCOL II, Inc., dba Artbeads.com  
11901 137th Ave Ct KPN  
Gig Harbor, Washington 98329

Email Address:  
support@artbeads.com

Telephone number:  
253-857-3433

Effective as of May 15, 2017
